COLE MYERS

Certified Full Stack Developer

CONTACT

cole.myers.cole@proton.me

Brandon, FL, 33511 💿

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Computer Science University of Tampa, FL 2009 - 2013 2225 N Lois Ave, Tampa, FL 33607,

SKILLS

Git

React.js SQL(MySQL, MongoDB) JavaScript Java C++ jQuery Express Node.js GitHub Laravel Firebase

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Golang developer with 7 years of experience and a passion for clean, efficient code. Recognized for skills in data structures, software architecture, and system design. Eager to join a team of experienced developers and help build world-class software products.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer

BravDev

Mar 2019 - Jul 2021

- Used understanding of React fundamentals to promote better component lifecycle practices, increasing turnaround speed by 23% with 100% deadline adherence.
- Communicated with other teams and senior management to adapt 50+ clients' websites to adapt to changing industry standards.
- Introduced wider use of isomorphic React and Node.js for web applications, decreasing load times by roughly 35%.
- Followed documentation to always remain up-to-speed on what needs to be updated in response to new release versions.

Golang Developer

ASPTech

Mar 2017 - Jan 2019

- Developed and maintained Golang microservices for a large-scale, high-throughput trading platform with 100+ developers in the team.
- Implemented RESTful APIs to connect frontend applications with backend services using Go channels and goroutines.
- Designed and implemented highly scalable solutions by leveraging concurrency primitives such as multi-threading, mutexes, semaphores etc., along with best practices like TDD (Test Driven Development).
- Participated in code reviews of other engineers' work and ensured that all code adheres to company's coding standards & guidelines.
- Used tools such as Git, Jira, Slack for version control, bug tracking and communication respectively.

Rust Developer

Wipro

May 2015 - Dec 2021

- Developed and maintained Rust microservices for a large-scale, high-throughput trading platform with 100+ developers in the team.
- Implemented RESTful APIs to connect frontend applications with backend services using Rust channels and rust routines.
- Designed and implemented highly scalable solutions by leveraging concurrency primitives such as multi-threading, mutexes, semaphores etc., along with best practices like TDD (Test Driven Development).
- Participated in code reviews of other engineers' work and ensured that all code adheres to company's coding standards & guidelines.
- Used tools such as Git, Jira, Slack for version control, bug tracking and communication respectively.